Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you,
you are watching You Dariel, I am your
own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. The credit for today's
video goes to this sir's
comment. Sir, thank you very much for your comment.
As
you all know that every day one video on the channel
comes according to your questions, suggestions and comments, so
do tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be related to. To stay
connected to the channel to get the videos on time,
for that like and share the video, do
not forget to subscribe to the channel and turn on all the notification bells and
join the membership by clicking on Join Membership as per your convenience. In today's
video, we will learn about the Easy Grow Plan of III Potential Life
Insurance Company Limited.
But
before that, let us tell you that the money you invest in a ULIP plan has
market-
related risk, hence
invest with proper understanding and planning. There are
16 different fund options available in this plan,
such as you have selected the fund option,
chosen the portfolio strategy,
then paid the premium to the
insurance company.  The premium was
invested in the market, in which whatever
happened to you, as soon as the policy term is completed,
at the date of the maturity, whatever is the
available fund value will be given to you,
which you can take in one go or in installments.
Before moving ahead, we will know
about the eligibility criteria of ICICI Potential Life's Easy Grow Plan. If we watch the
video on full screen, then
we come to know that the age limit for taking this plan is from
zero to 55
years, that is, this plan can be taken even for minors.
If your premium
payment term is from 5 years to 15 years, then
in such a case, the minimum policy term will be the
premium payment term plus five years
and the maximum will be up to 40 years.
In such a case, the maturity age limit will be from
18 years to 75
years. If you take the whole life cover option, then
you will get the premium payment term from 5 years to
15 years.
To withdraw the policy, you will get 99 rupees.
Subtract your age from 99. The maturity age
limit is maximum 99 years only. Regular pay
means premium payment for the same number of years as the policy term.
So, in such a case, the
policy term will be from 15 to 40 years and the maturity
age limit will be from 18 to 75 years. Rest of the
entry limits are same from 0 to 55
years. The premium limit in this plan is from
₹1 to ₹1 lakh per year as per
the policy brochure which is available on their website. The
minimum top-up premium
limit is ₹1.
You have the choice of
taking the sum assured up to 7 times the annual premium or 10 times the annual premium. If
you have paid a top-up premium, then you can choose from
1.25 times your top-up premium i.e.
1.25 times or 10 times.
10 times the top-up premium.  By
choosing that,
you can take sum assured of top up premium.
Talking about the benefits of ICICI Potential Life's Easy Grow Plan, you
know that you take this plan only because of life cover
and you get tax benefits
if your annual premium is Rs.  If the sum assured is
less than Rs 1 lakh, then first of all let's talk about the death benefit.
Summer short and top up summer
short will be added. If yes, then
105% of the premium paid will be calculated and
then it will be compared with the fund value.
Whichever is higher among the three will be the
death benefit which will be paid to the nominee.
Now you should watch the video in full screen
so that you can understand about the return of mortality
and policy administration charges.
You are getting returns from these charges. When will you get them?
As soon as the sixth year of the policy is over, then the
mortality rate and
policy administration charge levied in the first month of the first year will be the
return you will get in the first month of the sixth year of the policy
and it will be added to the fund value.
As you can see, the
policy
administration charge and mortality charge levied in the first month of the first year got added
in the first month of the sixth year of the policy. The
mortality charge and policy administration charge levied in the second month of the first year got
added to your fund value in the second month of the sixth year of the policy.  In the same
way, it will keep getting
added to your fund value during your policy term but it will
start from the sixth year of the policy.
You get maturity booster in it.
According to the policy brochure,
whatever be your premium payment term and whatever be
your premium payment term or
policy term,
you will get 0.5% maturity booster of your fund value. I am telling you
this age of average fund value in the policy
brochure which is available on their website. You
can make up to 20% of the value and
you can make this partial withdrawal till
your fund balance is two times your annual premium
i.e. maximum limit is reached.
If the
fund value falls less than two times your annual premium, then you will
not be able to withdraw. There
is also a facility of systematic withdrawal, same conditions
apply as on partial withdrawal. Just
what percentage of fund value you
want and in which mode, you have to
decide at the time of taking the plan.
You can increase and decrease premium payment in the plan.  You
can do term plan but the minimum premium
payment term will have to be 6 years. In such a case,
you can also increase or decrease the policy term.
The limit on age is what
I told you in the beginning. If we
talk about the portfolio strategy of ICICI Easy Grow Plan, then you will get four options
in it. The first is life cycle based
portfolio strategy. For example,
if your age at the time of taking the plan is between 0 to 25 years, then in such a case, whatever your portfolio will be, 80% will be in multi-cap growth fund i.e. in equity, 20% will be in income fund i.e. in debt. Now similarly, if
your age becomes 26 to 35 years, then
75% will be in equity i.e. in multi-cap
growth fund, 25% in debt i.e.
in income fund. So you can understand that
as our age increases, our
risk appetite reduces.
Normally, right, that 1% is on top 1 or 2% of
people who do not have it, the rest of the normal
people get it automatically, so in such a situation,
As the age increases, the
company automatically rebalances the portfolio on a quarterly basis.
Portfolio Strategy: Now here is a
combination of equity and debt. Multi-cap
growth fund, equity income fund, debt 75%,
equity 25%, income bond income fund. Right,
as soon as there is an upward movement of 10%
in the multi-cap growth fund, that movement, that is, the
gain which has
exceeded 75% of your investment, that is,
three times the income fund, will be
transferred to the liquid or money fund/money market fund. This ratio will be
maintained. Even if there is a downward movement of 10%, the
units which were increased will be
rebalanced to
maintain the 75:25 percent ratio.
Then there is the fixed portfolio
strategy, in which you will choose the fund and
you will also get ultimate free switches,
but the minimum amount of switches, that is, the
value, should be ₹. In this,
you also get the facility of automatic transfer
from one fund to another.  The
fourth is your target asset
allocation strategy, which we
also call targeted asset allocation strategy. Here
you have chosen the fund and
decided on the premium allocation. Accordingly,
investment will be made in the fund chosen by you.
Now, before moving ahead, let us
understand the details of the charges of ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company Limited's Easy Grow plan. There will be
no premium allocation charge in any plan, that is,
if there is no premium allocation charge in the ULIP plan, then it is a
good thing. The maximum
policy administration
charge that you can incur every month
is limited to ₹5000000. The policy
discontinuance charge can be charged from ₹000 to ₹6000,
depending on how much premium you were paying
annually and in which year.
You already know the discontinuance charge. It depends on your age,
your health and how much cover you are taking. We will play the
video on full
screen. Now, the
percentage that you see here is of Multi Cap Balance Fund.
Further,
99.94 p.a. means per annum. It means that the
rate of return of all these funds from the time these
fund options became available till now,
i.e. till December 2024, is
mentioned here. It will keep increasing or decreasing as per
time. For example, the
average rate of return of Active Assets Allocation Balance Fund is
9.17 p.a.,
Secure Opportunity Fund is 6.47 p.a., Income
Fund is 7.75 p.a. Similarly, Mitke Fund, which is
their new fund option, has
given a return at the rate of 32.5 p.a., so
why is this being mentioned so that
you can decide which fund you would like to choose. Any fund with
single digit returns is a debt
oriented fund, any fund with double digit returns is an
equity oriented fund, which means there is
risk there. In policy discontinuance fund,
0.5% fund management charge is levied on your annual average fund value.
In money market fund, your annual fund management charge is 0.5%.  A
fund management charge of 0.75% of the average fund value will be levied for all other
fund options. A
fund management charge of 1.35% of your annual average fund value will be levied for all other fund options. If you open the
PDF
video in full screen, the
policy brochure says that if the age is 30 years
and the premium payment is
taken for a term limited premium of Rs. 50,000 per annum, then
in such a case,
10 times the annual premium i.e. a life cover of ₹1 lakh is
taken. If the premium payment for 10 years is 20
years, then a premium of ₹1 lakh will have to be paid in 10 years.
If you
pause the video and carefully look at the fund management
page, then you would know what is the
rate of return on the Maximizer V fund that they have chosen. If you did
look at it, then let us know in the comment section. At the
rate of %, the rate of return can be 12135/1661.
Now, these are fractions;
you
get returns according to the performance of the fund. Otherwise, if you
receive the policy bond and then
feel that you want to cancel it.  So,
you can cancel the policy within 15 days,
not after that, after that the locking period gets
applied. Before taking a Yuli plan, you should
understand it properly and plan it only then you should
take it because it is a
subject to market race. Thank you all, take care of
yourself. Happy New Year
[Music]